let's meet your canvases
each year hundreds of thousands of brave
men and women serve in the Armed Forces
we have some veterans who are here with
us today we will also be joined by some
families who've lost loved ones artists
today you must help these families and
veterans on their road to healing by
engraving an item that's an emblem of
military service dog tags must create a
personalized design commemorating either
the fallen soldier or the veterans
service it's one of those things that
people are really proud to wear but the
reason why you have to wear them
definitely carries a dark side to it
it's gonna be pretty emotional day I
think make sure you give them a design
they can be proud of forever good luck
Hoos we're memorializing my son Bryan
with these dog tags all we really want
to see is how they deal with this
situation this is a very intense
challenge my fallen hero is my husband
I'm sorry to hear that our prior
military myself thank you for your
service
I'm actually still active-duty Air Force
oh really I'm awesome I have 24 fallen
friends if you could take each one of
their operator initials around like the
seven cell parachute my son Jordan was
the United States Marine and he was
killed by a suicide bomber the truck
exploded the bed
Jordan and his comrade we were killed
instantly as a parent I can't even
handle my kid getting I cannot fathom
what you guys have to go through you
know you're loved and lost something
like this today in high school we just
said mom I just don't know what I want
to do with my life one of the last
letters that he wrote home to me he
roped I finally found a place for me I
love it here more than anything I'm
doing the best I can to be the best
soldier I really want to win this but
I'm putting that out of my head because
there is a higher stake now we're trying
to represent somebody who's fallen it's
her son Brian's life and I don't know
that I can do it justice
three
that's it it really turned out well
Jenny you know Christopher I can't thank
you enough for being a part of the scene
that's uh it was such an honor -
pleasure to meet you I want to give this
to you and I want you to give this to
your son no way I do it was pretty
moving it was pretty powerful I'm
definitely gonna go home and present it
to my son in a pass the story along to
him some of the most meaningful tattoos
celebrate a personal victory one of the
greatest triumphs is surviving cancer
your canvases today have all survived
one of the deadliest forms breast cancer
many of them beat cancer by having a
mastectomy to remove the breast some
women choose to reconstruct their
breasts but the scars remain and these
scars are in a very sensitive area so
it's even more challenging to pull off a
flawless tattoo but that's exactly what
you must do for these canvases as a
cancer survivor I know what it's like to
stare death in the face this tattoo
represents life and it represents the
good things that come out of fighting
let's meet your canvases today we have
to do the most important tattoo that
we've ever had to do
it's one of the only tattoos you can
give somebody that actually helps change
their life these canvases are looking
for great work out of these final four
artists and that's what we're hoping for
as well this is a way to not only
commemorate what they've been through
but to beautify it these guys need to
really step up and give them everything
they can my idea was a dandelion on the
side blowing across transforming into
butterflies I hope that getting this
tattoo is really going to make me feel
like I have my life back
cancer doesn't owe me you just put your
faith in me I'm gonna give you a
beautiful tattoo it's gonna be a breeze
I want to get the cross on the one side
is my mom died from breast cancer and
then flowers on the other side I want a
flowering vine across the whole chest I
feel like a war went on in my chest this
is like a battlefield and I would rather
have something beautiful so this is the
one side that I've got mapped out for
you
still okay oh my gosh I'm babysitting
for six hours
no I didn't chemo I can do this
it's nice that there's survivors like
you that can go out there or like a look
at something in the world to have that
positive spin I think is really really
cool the biggest challenge is going to
be to make sure that she gets exactly
what she wants and that she feels
beautiful
I can't believe that while you're
sitting ranking again
I think it's really good I think we can
commit to that as long as you feel it
yeah I'm good
don't feel feminine but I think their
tax is gonna bring that feminine
three
that's it times up machines down no more
ink
I've been more than a pinkie with this
than any flower of ever done in my whole
life
pretty okay I love the highlights it is
perfect
let's meet your guest artists and your
canvases
hi guys welcome and thank you so much
for being here approximately 400,000
Americans have Down syndrome Down
syndrome is the most commonly occurring
chromosomal condition that occurs when a
person has an extra copy of chromosome
21 individuals with Down syndrome
experience cognitive delays but the
effect is usually mild to moderate and
is not an indicator of the many
strengths and talents each individual
possesses for some art is one of those
talents each of today's guest artists
with Down syndrome has brought a loved
one with them who wants their artwork
tattooed on them forever please tell us
why you're here today this is my
brother-in-law Joe I'm here to get a
tattoo of the sign language symbol for I
love you to show the positive impact Joe
has had in my life this is my brother
Matt I'm having him design a tattoo to
mark the relationship that we have yeah
apparently a thunderstorm this is my
daughter Nicole she's been my
inspiration and driving force since the
day she was born I'm so proud of my
daughter Marissa and all that he's
accomplished and I can't wait to have a
tattoo with her amazing artwork this is
my brother Patrick and I'm here to get a
meaningful tattoo and I also want people
asking me about it because I want there
to be a conversation about Down syndrome
and I think that is tattoos the perfect
way to do that this is my sister
Stephanie she's an artist in Los Angeles
I want to get a tattoo of her artwork on
me to show that I really believe in her
as an artist this is my son Jay and I'm
here today for him he said it was his
wish come true there's times where you
question are we really doing something
that somebody really wants to have for
the rest of their life and this is one
of those moments that you don't even
have to ask any questions this is why
I'm a tattoo artist I just want to do
something really special
how are you let's have a seat you figure
out what we're gonna do let's do it
should I just give you some paper and
let you go crazy there's a lot more at
stake today in this challenge is given
these guest artists a chance to be part
of something amazing and it's giving
their loved ones a gift that they can
take with them the rest of the life to
show the connection they have when life
hits you you can always make me smile so
to have incorporated some smiley face
between the two of you this will be
awesome you and I we're gonna do it all
right right you can do whatever you want
okay I'm already into this kind of stuff
you know it's cool the meaning behind
this is so deep
blood is definitely thicker than water
the black tattoo ink in these is
actually my brother's ashes when he
passed away we took his ashes and I got
tattooed with him this way he will
always be a part of me and you go
everywhere with me Anna and I feel like
that's powerful like what's going on
here today cool perfect I like it steady
yeah look at steady yeah this kid is so
happy then I'm working with him he's
turning it on and off so I look like a
crazy person I'm the guy who's got 666
tattooed on in pentagrams and he just
looks right past that just to be around
people that have just unconditional love
for everybody is like worth everything
check this out man machines down no more
ink
we did good huh yeah it was awesome
just like something he would do thank
you for hanging out today thank you very
my god that is awesome
but I get the job where's yes for this
flash challenge your canvases all have
loved ones with a condition that has
permanently changed their appearance
sometimes this can bring unwanted
attention and embarrassment that they
live with every day to show their
support and solidarity your canvases
want an exact replica of their loved
ones condition permanently tattooed on
their skin let's meet your canvases
oh my god hi guys thanks for joining us
please tell us what you'd like done I
like to get a tattoo of my son's insulin
pump on my side I want to get a replica
of his skin grafts from a burn on my leg
and foot this is my grandson and I'm
getting a replica of his cochlear
implant on my head this is my daughter
Liliana and I would like a replica of
her scar across my stomach I would like
to get a tattoo replica of his zipper
scar on my chest
good job Tom what's going on buddy brave
little kids today we're asking you to
shed the pressures you have in this room
be human and be good tattooers for these
folks today it's all about that and your
time starts now
today the artist wanted to exact
replicas so that the children can bond
with their parents like look mommy daddy
has what I have he fell on a bonfire
burns is like if I have a two he can say
hey look my dad's got the same thing as
me same thing happened to my daughter
serious she was two at the time she
ended up falling in the fire as well it
was the scariest moment of my life as a
parent I was 17 when I had my daughter
it was a kid having a kid she saved my
life because I was going down just a
really dark path as soon as I found out
that I was pregnant I stopped everything
I got into tattooing I'm completely and
utterly stove I miss her but at the same
time it makes me remember what I'm here
and what I'm fighting for and I'm
fighting for my little one game time she
was born premature and she had to be in
the hospital for a year she had nine
surgeries in her intestines yeah this
scar might make you feel embarrassed but
you went through something really hard
and you survived
I show you that you're stronger than
when you
four three two one
that's it machines down time is up no
more ink
awesome oh my god that's my baby oh
there's still some work thank you so
much
Oh got a rad little guy with you yeah